betterworldbooks.com 2016-06-21

# BetterWorldBooks.com Privacy Policy

The security of your personal information is of the utmost importance to us. In order to fulfill orders, we share your address and the items you have purchased with our third party sellers. We do not sell your information to anyone and hold our partners to the same standard.

General Overview

The purpose of this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.

Better World Books is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect about you to facilitate commercial transactions and to provide you with a more personalized experience. We have created this Privacy Policy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to protecting the privacy of all of our customers and visitors. The following Privacy Policy discloses the information-gathering and dissemination practices and policies of Better World Books. 

This Privacy Policy informs you about the following: 

  1. The types of information that may be collected 
  2. How the information is collected 
  3. How we use the information that we collect 
  4. With whom the information that we collect may be shared 
  5. The choices that you have about Better World Books collecting, using, and sharing your information
  6. The security precautions that are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information
  7. Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards
  8. Links to other web sites
  9. A special note for parents concerning privacy
  10. Limitation of Liability
  11. Notification of changes and acceptance of is Privacy Policy
  12. Correcting and updating personally identifiable information
  13. Whom do I contact with questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy?

1\. Types of information that may be collected

The personally identifiable information we collect is used to facilitate delivery of products and/or services to our customers. In the process of providing these products and/or services, we require our customers to provide certain personally identifiable information. Specific details may include, but are not limited to the following and may be subject to change:

  * In the case of program registrations: We may require all users and/or customers wishing to participate in our programs or contests to complete a Participant Registration Form. During this registration process we would generate and collect certain personally identifiable information

  * The personally identifiable information that may be collected from our customers in completion of a Participant Registration Form: Customer's first name, last name, zip code, Twitter user i.d. (if applicable), Facebook user i.d. (if applicable), telephone number, age and email address. Some program participants also will be required to provide additional personally identifiable information such as a shipping address.

  * In the case of product purchases: In order to complete the purchase of a product, an on-line credit card transaction may be required. During this process we generate and collect certain verifiable personally identifiable information.

  * The verifiable personally identifiable information that may be collected from our customers in completion of a product purchase: the customer's first and last name, first and last name of the credit card owner, credit card billing address, credit card number, credit card expiration date, card verification value (“CVV”), customer's shipping address, phone number, and email address.

  * If a customer sends us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, we may collect such information into a file specific to such customer.

2\. How the information is collected

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the web site located at the u.r.l., [ www.BetterWorldBooks.com](http://www.betterworldbooks.com/) (the “Site”), including but not limited to those described below:

  * **Registration.** You may be asked first to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to order our products or participate in a program or a service feature (including, without limitation, our Blog) offered on or through the Site. 

  * **Newsletters and Site Emails.** We may offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Site, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our business partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Site. You may cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Site or, in some instances, in the designated area of certain newsletters or emails. 

  * **Contests or Sweepstakes.** We may operate contests and sweepstakes through the Site, which may require registration. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes. We may ask your permission to allow us to post publicly some of your information on the Site, such as on a winners page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Site, and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we have no control over the information collected and accordingly urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating. 

  * **Surveys or Voting.** From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you via surveys or voting polls. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey.

  * **Cookies.** As with many Websites, the Site uses standard technology called "cookies," which are small data files that are transferred to your computer when you allow your browser to accept cookies. Cookies automatically identify your Web browser to the Site whenever you visit the Site, and make using the Site easier for you by saving your passwords, purchases, and preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Site, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Site are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Site. Cookies may also allow the Site to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. In addition, the Site uses cookies in the order and checkout process. If you do not have cookies enabled on your browser, you may experience problems ordering our products. 

  * **IP Addresses and Click-stream Data.** We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data for purposes of system administration. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. Our computers identify your computer by its IP address. When you request Web pages from the Site, our computers log your IP address. 

Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages from the Site. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time spent reviewing the page, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Site, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content on the Site and advertising, and the like. 

  * **Transaction Information.** If you buy any products or services offered on our Site, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including financial information such as a credit card number and expiration date and general contact, billing and shipping information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested to deliver the product(s) or service(s) that you order, and to invoice you. Credit card numbers and other billing information are securely collected and transmitted to payment processor(s) through encrypted means for your protection. Other information is securely collected and stored through encrypted means for your protection. 

3\. How we use the information that we collect

We internally use personally identifiable information about our customers to fulfill orders placed on the Site, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze site usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our Site's content and layout. We believe these uses allow us to improve our Site and provide better service to our customers.

We occasionally may use a customer's email address and, in rare situations mailing address or phone number, to contact a customer regarding administrative or billing matters. 

We also may use information in the file we maintain about a customer to resolve disputes. 

4\. With whom the information that we collect may be shared

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Better World Books, and we do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties.

Better World Books shares your personal information with:

  * **Third party providers of products and services you order:** If you buy a product on the Site that is fulfilled by a third party, we share your personal information with that third party for the purpose of fulfilling your order. Examples of this include, but may not be limited to, Marketplace orders (orders of books listed on the Site and fulfilled by independent booksellers) and new book orders (which may be fulfilled directly by a wholesaler). 

  * **Other entities owned by Better World Books:** We manage or may manage in the future other web sites owned by Better World Books. We may share your personal information within Better World Books and/or its affiliated entities (if any) in order to provide you a better experience on all of our web sites. 

  * **Service providers, subcontractors and agents who perform services on our behalf:** We provide personal information to third party service providers, subcontractors, and agents that work under contract on our behalf to provide certain services. These third parties do not have the right to use the personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by us. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information.

  * **Credit Card Companies:** Credit card transactions are handled by third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors who receive credit card numbers and other personal information from us to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions.

  * **Protection of Better World Books and Others:** We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Better World Books, our users, or other third parties. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. However, this disclosure does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Policy.

  * **Business Transfers:** As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or other business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets, but such information remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the event that Better World Books or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets to the acquiror in such transaction. In addition, if Better World Books becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, personal information may be provided to the entities and advisors involved in such transaction, subject to a confidentiality agreement.

From time to time, we may send you offers from Better World Books, and/or our partners based upon the information you have provided us. Other than the foregoing or as provided in an amendment to this Privacy Policy, we will not intentionally share your personally-identifiable information with third parties for promotional purposes.

5\. The choices that I have about Better World Books collecting, using, and sharing my information

It is possible for you to use much of our site without giving us any personally identifiable information. When you do register with us or give us personally identifiable information, you will have an opportunity at the time we collect your information -- to limit e-mail communications from Better World Books. You can request at any time that Better World Books not send future e-mail to you by unsubscribing from the communication through links contained therein (typically in the footer of the e-mail). If you require further assistance, you may contact us at help@BetterWorldBooks.com. Please note that such requests do not include e-mail of a purely administrative nature (i.e., you cannot opt out of receiving order confirmations, shipping confirmations, or arrival confirmations). They do, however, include opting out of special offers and newsletters.

6\. The security precautions that are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information

We use industry standard efforts and have established reasonable security procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally-identifiable information. However, please keep in mind that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet and/or the World Wide Web, and, notwithstanding anything to the contrary stated in this Privacy Policy, Better World Books assumes no responsibility, and expressly disclaims liability, with regard to the loss or disclosure of your personally identifiable information due to causes outside of its direct control.

7\. Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards

The Site may make chat rooms, forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personally identifiable information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personally identifiable information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. Better World Books cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personally identifiable information in these areas.

8\. Links to other Websites Boards

You should be aware that when you are on the Site you could be directed to other web sites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Site onto a different Website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use the Site's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other Websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personally identifiable information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a Website that is linked to our Site, you should consult that site's privacy policy before providing any personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you submit to third-party Websites, including, without limitation, any Websites that may be connected to our Site by hypertext link or otherwise.

9\. A special note for parents concerning privacy 

We do not encourage children to participate in providing us with any personally identifiable information. We ask that children (12 years of age and under) do not submit any personally identifiable information to us.

We support the guidelines and regulatory requirements provided in the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA): <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html>

10\. Limitation of Liability

By providing us with any personally identifiable information you expressly and unconditionally release and hold harmless Qumpus, Inc., d.b.a. Better World Books and its shareholders, subsidiaries, affiliates, directors, officers, trustees, governors, employees, volunteers and agents (collectively, the “Releasees”) from any and all liability for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected personally identifiable information. In addition, while Better World Books makes efforts to ensure the proper and appropriate use of data provided by Better World Books to third-party companies, promotional partners or vendors, the Releasees are not liable for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected personally identifiable information by such third parties. 

11\. Limitation of Liability

By using this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of our Privacy Policy. Better World Books may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, any such changes will be posted on this Privacy Policy, so that Better World Books may keep its users informed of its information collection practices. Accordingly, we recommend that you consult this Privacy Policy frequently so that you are aware of our latest privacy policy and/or any changes to this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Site shall constitute your acceptance of any such new or revised Privacy Policy. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will send such person an email notifying him/her of such changes and giving him/her the option as to whether to allow us to use such information in such different manner. Without such consent, we will use personally identifiable information in accordance with the privacy policy under which it was collected. 

12\. Correcting and updating personally identifiable information

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Site, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct or update the personally identifiable information you have provided to us. This can be done by making changes to your profile, by using an option out message in an email, or by [submitting a ticket](https://support.betterworldbooks.com/index.php?/Tickets/Submit) to us. 

13\. Whom do I contact with questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact Better World Books by sending a letter to:

Better World Books  
11680 Great Oaks Way, Suite 250  
Alpharetta, GA 30022   
You may also contact us by e-mail by [submitting a ticket](https://support.betterworldbooks.com/index.php?/Tickets/Submit). 

For your reference you can find the previous version of our privacy policy here.
